Marco Catapano

Software Engineer

7 years of experience focused in back-end application development. I spent these years with the intent of getting continuously better in software engineering. I have always had and I still have curiosity towards languages in order to improve everyday; learning is a never ending process, especially in IT.

About me

☆ via Modenese 5, Pistoia 51100, PT★ +39 3468772332

marco.catapano.93@gmail.com

™ catapano-marco@mail.com

4 12/05/1993

LinkedIn

GitHub

Experience

present - 2022/05

Engineer II @ Trade Republic

- Develop and extend BE µservices across multiple atoms
- Tech: Kotlin, Spring, GH Actions, Elasticsearch, Postgres, RabbitMQ, k8s

2022/04 -2021/05

Software Engineer @ Prima Assicurazioni

- Develop FE and BE of the Agents' platform
- Tech: Rust, Elm, GraphQL, k8s, RabbitMQ, PostgreSQL

2021/05 -2018/09

Software Engineer @ Extra RED S.r.l.

- Develop Apache Camel routes and Spring REST services
- DevOps engineering with OCP 3.x and Jenkins
- Tech: Camel, Spring, Jenkins, OCP, Java8+, Gitlab, RDBMS, ActiveMQ

2018/05 -2016/09

Backend Developer @ M.E.T.A. S.r.l.

- Develop features in digital publishing back-ends
- Extending websites of cultural authorities
- Tech: PHP, MySQL, Solr, Git

2016/08 -2015/12

Backend Developer @ SITER S.r.l.

- Extend company main product either by changing the codebase or by creating external executables (e.g. SOAP consumers, IMAP desktop apps, etc.)
- Tech: VB6, C#, Java 7, .NET 4, RDBMS

2015/10 -2015/07

Backend Developer (trainee) @ SITER S.r.l.

- Develop a SOAP service and consumer for the company's main product DB
- Tech: VB6, C#, Java 7, .NET 4, RDBMS

Misc.

In compliance with the GDPR and Italian Legislative Decree no. 196 dated 30/06/2003, I hereby authorize the recipient of this document to use and process my personal details for the purpose of recruiting and selecting staff and I confirm to be informed of my rights in accordance to art. 7 of the above mentioned Decree.

Tech skills

Languages:

Java, Kotlin, Rust, C#, Elm, PHP, VB, Golang (basic), JS (basic), C (basic), Groovy (basic), F# (basic), SH (basic)

Technologies:

Spring, JavaEE, Quarkus, Apache Camel, GraphQL, .NET Core, Maven, Gradle, NuGet, Cargo, GitHub Actions, k8s, OCP, Jenkins

Tools:

Git, Docker, IntelliJ IDEA, VSCode, Visual Studio, Postman, SOAPui, Insomnia

Worked with:

Openshift, EAP, PostgreSQL, Karaf, MySQL, Elasticsearch, Terraform, ActiveMQ, RabbitMQ, Datadog, GitHub, Jira, SonarCloud, (bits of) AWS

Natural languages

Italian: native speaker **English:** professional (B2+)

Education

Bachelor's Degree in C.S.

Score: 110/110 w/ Honors

Subjects: algorithms, data structures, functional programming, OOP, basic math, formal languages, RDBMS, computer architecture and networks

High-school diploma in Business, Accountancy, and Programming

Score: 100/100

Subjects: economics, applied math, IT